Guide to the New York City COVID-19 Web Activism Collection TAM.798
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Christian Smalls Twitter, May 2020-ongoing; Smalls, Chris (Box Electronic Records)
  Christian "Chris" Smalls, a management assistant at Amazon Warehouse JFK98 located on Staten Island, was fired by Amazon on March 30th, 2020 after organizing a strike to call attention to the lack of protections for workers at the facility. Documentation of Smalls' labor and COVID-19 activism begins with a March 30th post in which Smalls records the inside of the JFK98 warehouse break room where social distancing rules are not enforced and workers are without personal protective equipment. Smalls' Twitter feed includes still image and video posts documenting the walkout, artwork depicting Smalls, calls for action, fundraising campaigns related to supporting striking Amazon workers, and social justice focused events and programming in which Smalls is a participant.
- Crisis brings the Hate, We bring Rainbows, June 2020-February 2022; Talen, Bill (Box Electronic Records)
  CW: This video contains the violent arrest of Reverend Bill Talen, of Reverend Billy and the Church of Stop Shopping, and harmful racist, homophobic, and transphobic language spoken by Franklin Graham of Samaritan's Purse. During the 2020 COVID-19 crisis, Samaritan's Purse - an evangelical organization led by Franklin Graham - constructed a field hospital in Central Park. Given the organization's stance on LGBTQIA issues; homophobic, transphobic, and Islamophobic statements made by Graham; and the organization's requirement that individuals working for Samaritan's Purse must be Christians who oppose same-sex marriage, the hospital was met with criticism by LGBTQIA leaders, progressive religious leaders, and elected officials. LGBTQIA organizations, and others, protested the field hospital, inclusive of this action taken by Reverend Billy, in which he raises a rainbow flag next to the hospital. In May of 2020, the field hospital discharged its patients and dismantled its tents.
- Transportation Alternatives- Bike Match, June 2020-July 2021; Transportation Alternatives (Organization) (Box Electronic Records)
  Transportation Alternatives' (TA) mission is to reclaim New York City's streets from the automobile and advocate for better bicycling, walking, and public transit for all New Yorkers. With 100,000 active supporters, TA fights for the installation of infrastructure improvements that reduce speeding and traffic crashes, save lives and improve everyday transportation for all New Yorkers. Since their founding in 1973, TA's work has led to he extraordinary growth of bicycling, the launch of Citi Bike and the introduction of innovations to city streets, like Complete Streets, parking-protected bike lanes, automated speed enforcement cameras, public plazas, Select Bus Service and Neighborhood Slow Zones. TA activists are currently leading the fight to improve infrastructure for bicycling and walking on scores of local streets and to change traffic enforcement policy and practices citywide.
- West Side Federation for Senior and Supportive Housing, June 2020-July 2021; West Side Federation for Senior Housing (Box Electronic Records)
  West Side Federation For Senior and Supportive Housing, Inc. (WSFSSH) was formed in 1976 by a coalition of social service agencies, religious institutions, and community organizations. They work to meet the diverse needs of older people and persons living with special needs. Their first building, the Marseilles, opened in 1980 and provided 134 independent apartments to low income elderly and handicapped individuals. In addition to serving independent seniors, they now serve frail elderly individuals, older persons living with serious mental illnesses, homeless individuals, persons living with physically handicapping conditions, grandparents raising their grandchildren, and families. They currently house over 1,800 people in 24 buildings located on the Upper West Side, and in Harlem, Chelsea, and the Bronx.
- WSFSSH Locations, June 2020-July 2021; West Side Federation for Senior Housing (Box Electronic Records)
  Map of West Side Federation for Senior and Supportive Housing Locations.
- Workers Need Childcare, June 2020-January 2021 (Box Electronic Records)
  Workers Need Childcare connects parents to free and low-cost childcare options during COVID-19. They rely on remote volunteers across the country, but their service is designed for parents in New York City's essential workforce (e.g. health care, education, shipping, media, warehousing, grocery and food production, utilities, domestic workers) who need affordable childcare options during COVID-19.
- Workers Need Childcare Flyer, June 2020-February 2022; Workers Need Childcare (Box Electronic Records)
  Flyer for the Workers Need Childcare organization.
- Workers Need Childcare Parent Volunteers Role Description, June 2020-February 2022; Workers Need Childcare (Box Electronic Records)
  Role descriptions for volunteers for the Workers Need Childcare organization.
- Coronavirus Resource Kit, June 2020 (Box Electronic Records)
  Google document linked from the SWOP Brooklyn website's COVID resource page. A general resource kit related to COVID.
- Protections against ICE Raids, June 2020 (Box Electronic Records)
  Google document linked from the SWOP Brooklyn website's COVID resource page. Resource list for migrants and undocumented immigrants related to ICE raids.